{
  "fileName": "Quiz Miller_Spoolman Living in the Environment 16e, Chapter, Chapter 15.pdf.txt",
  "questions": [
    {
      "number": 1,
      "question": "Fossil fuels and ________ are nonrenewable types of energy.",
      "choices": [
        "none of the choices",
        "hydropower",
        "biomass",
        "wind"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 2,
      "question": "________ is/are used as the raw material(s) in the production of cleaning fluids, pesticides, plastics, medicines, and synthetic fibers.",
      "choices": [
        "Petrochemicals",
        "Coal",
        "Natural gas",
        "Gasoline"
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 3,
      "question": "The thick, gooey liquid consisting of hundreds of different hydrocarbon molecules that is pumped out of the ground is called",
      "choices": [
        "conventional oil.",
        "light oil.",
        "all of the choices",
        "crude oil."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 4,
      "question": "Refining crude oil",
      "choices": [
        "increases its net energy yield.",
        "separates different components based on boiling point and volatility.",
        "all of the choices",
        "produces light oil."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 5,
      "question": "Oil prices in 2008 were about",
      "choices": [
        "$100.00 per barrel.",
        "$10.00 per barrel.",
        "$200.00 per barrel.",
        "$50.00 per barrel."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 6,
      "question": "Saudi Arabia has the world\u0027s largest crude oil reserves at 25%. The nation with the second-largest crude oil reserves is",
      "choices": [
        "Venezuela.",
        "Canada.",
        "Kuwait.",
        "Iraq."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 7,
      "question": "In the U.S., the projected trend of automakers is",
      "choices": [
        "a shift toward cars that run on diesel fuel.",
        "a steep decline in sales of cars and trucks that get less than 40 miles per gallon.",
        "increased production of SUVs to meet consumer demand.",
        "a shift toward cars that carry many people to accommodate carpooling."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 8,
      "question": "The United States produces 9% of the world\u0027s oil but consumes",
      "choices": [
        "1%.",
        "39%.",
        "24%.",
        "85%."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 9,
      "question": "Oil recovery is not 100% efficient. Typically, ________ barrel(s) of oil is/are extracted for every ________ barrels of oil found.",
      "choices": [
        "1, 2",
        "2, 5",
        "3, 10",
        "1, 3"
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 10,
      "question": "Bitumen is a material found in",
      "choices": [
        "oil sand.",
        "petroleum.",
        "heavy oil.",
        "oil shale."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 11,
      "question": "The solid combustible mixture of hydrocarbons called kerogen is found in",
      "choices": [
        "oil shale.",
        "shale oil.",
        "bitumen.",
        "oil sand."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 12,
      "question": "Which of the following is true?",
      "choices": [
        "Conventional gas deposits often from beneath deposits of crude oil.",
        "Natural gas is almost pure methane.",
        "Natural gas is most often solidified for transport using high pressure at a very low temperature.",
        "Of the three fossil fuels, natural gas releases the least carbon dioxide when burned."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 13,
      "question": "Which statement regarding natural gas is false?",
      "choices": [
        "Natural gas is more expensive to extract than petroleum, however it is more versatile.",
        "At the current rate of consumption, conventional natural gas should last at least 50 years.",
        "Natural gas is less polluting than other fossil fuels.",
        "Natural gas is considered a bridge fuel to help make the transition to a more sustainable energy future."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 14,
      "question": "Which statement is true?",
      "choices": [
        "all of the choices",
        "Coal is the most abundant fossil fuel.",
        "Coal is the least polluting fossil fuel.",
        "Coal is the most efficient fossil fuel."
      ],
      "correct": 1
    },
    {
      "number": 15,
      "question": "Heat is the potential enemy of nuclear reactors. Excess heat is prevented and/or controlled by",
      "choices": [
        "a coolant (water).",
        "the cooling tower.",
        "all of the choices",
        "control rods."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 16,
      "question": "Nuclear power plants",
      "choices": [
        "have a lifespan of about 15-60 years, after which they may be renovated for additional use.",
        "can last virtually forever if properly maintained.",
        "have a lifespan of about 200 years, after which they must be decommissioned.",
        "have a lifespan of about 15-60 years, after which they must be decommissioned."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    },
    {
      "number": 17,
      "question": "A significant disadvantage of nuclear energy is that",
      "choices": [
        "we lack the expertise to make power plant facilities a safe operating environment.",
        "there have been, and probably will continue to be, many nuclear power plant failures.",
        "highly radioactive wastes cannot be completely and permanently disposed of at this time.",
        "uranium-containing ore will run out within a couple of decades."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 18,
      "question": "Nuclear power plants produce a significant amount of radioactive wastes that must be appropriately disposed of/contained. These wastes remain radioactive (and deadly!) for",
      "choices": [
        "thousands to hundreds of thousands of years.",
        "millions to tens of millions of years.",
        "hundreds of years.",
        "decades."
      ],
      "correct": 0
    },
    {
      "number": 19,
      "question": "Which of the following is not considered an appropriate option for the decommissioning of a nuclear power plant?",
      "choices": [
        "The plant is enclosed in a tomb that must be monitored for leaks for several thousand years.",
        "The plant has a physical barrier built around it, with fulltime security for 30-100 years.",
        "The plant is demolished using standard explosives, then covered with concrete, then clay, and finally soil.",
        "The plant is dismantled, with its components stored in a high-level nuclear waste storage facility."
      ],
      "correct": 2
    },
    {
      "number": 21,
      "question": "The process used to join two smaller atomic nuclei, releasing energy in the process, is called",
      "choices": [
        "nuclear fission.",
        "radiation.",
        "the nuclear fuel cycle.",
        "nuclear fusion."
      ],
      "correct": 3
    }
  ]
}